BENSON NDIWA

Nairobi, Kenya +254 707 357 072 bnkimtai@gmail.com

A solution-driven full stack web developer adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. I have proven experience developing consumer-focused web applications. I also possess good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, security and speed.

EXPERIENCE

Techno Brain Ltd — Software Development Engineer in Test

July 2022 - Present

As an SDET, I leveraged C#, .NET Frameworks, and Selenium to create and execute automated test scripts, ensuring quality and reliability of Microsoft products, while actively contributing to various features in Microsoft Teams.

Darna Limited, Nairobi — Software Engineer Intern

June 2021 - May 2022

Developed and implemented new features that improved system performance by 30%, reducing processing time and increasing efficiency.

The National Treasury, Nairobi — IT Support Attache

April 2019 - August 2019

Resolved complex technical issues and provided expert support, reducing downtime and increasing productivity for employees and partners.

EDUCATION

Multimedia University of Kenya, Nairobi — Degree

September 2017 - December 2022

Bsc Information Technology

CERTIFICATION

Azubi Africa, Nairobi - AWS Re/Start Program

May 2022 - August 2022

AWS Cloud Practitioner

SKILLS

Full Stack Web
Development
Desktop Applications
Bash Scripting
Docker, Linux
AWS Cloud Computing

PROGRAMMING

LANGUAGES

C#, .Net
React, React Native
Javascript, NodeJS
MongoDB,SQL
MySQL,MSSQL
PostgreSQL
PHP

LANGUAGES

English, Swahili

Github

https://github.com/Benso n306

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.co m/in/benson-kimtai-ndiw

<u>a</u>

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Web Application

An ecommerce web application with Cart, User dashboard and working payment options available. It also has an admin panel for management of orders, deliveries, products and delivery locations. Developed with React, Node.js, Express, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS

Real Estate Management System

A web application that enables real estate professionals to track residents, leases, maintenance tasks, collect rent, and handle finances to update operations and reduce costs. Developed with ASP.NET, MySQL, CSS and uses the Safaricom Daraja API for mobile payment.

Utulivu Shopping Cart

A web application that allows a customer to browse, grab a product off the shelf, and head to the checkout counter to make a purchase. It has capability for enabling instant mobile payment. Developed with React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS.

Hospital ERP

A web application that aims at bringing quality in patient care & management with various important utilities like easy & quick patient registration, instant access to patient's complete health history, integrated patient module with various other related departments and many more. Developed with PHP, Javascript, postgreSQL and uses Mpdf to generate pdf receipts and records.

Electronic Store

This project is a cross-platform mobile application built with React Native. It offers a seamless shopping experience with features like product browsing, cart management, and secure payment options, providing users with a convenient way to purchase products directly from their mobile devices. Developed with React Native, c#, Redis and MySQL.

Brindex Course Search

A course finder application to compare diploma, undergraduate and postgraduate courses from colleges, top universities and higher education institutions across Kenya, including entry requirements. Developed with c# ASP.NET, Javascript and MySQL

Weather App

The weather app project is a mobile application developed using the React Native framework. It provides real-time weather information and a sleek user interface, allowing users to easily check the weather forecast for their location and other desired locations. Developed with React Native, Flask, Redis and MongoDB.

PORTFOLIO

https://benndiwa.netlify.a